

Colella.john@gmail.com631 838 8222Brooklyn, NY

in
www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcolella
n
https://github.com/jmcolella

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript(JQuery), HTML5, CSS3, SQL **FRAMEWORKS:** Rails, Jekyll, Bootstrap, Materialize, Sinatra, React.js

PLATFORMS: Google Maps API, Yelp API, Twitter API DATABASES: PostgresSQL, ActiveRecord, SQLite TESTING: RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara FOREIGN LANGUAGES: Italian

SUMMARY

I am a web developer with an eye for design, skilled in Ruby, JavaScript, Rails, Bootstrap and Materialize. With experience working in fast-paced environments, I'm a team player who can work efficiently and collaboratively with others to meet hard deadlines. I have excellent communication and organizational skills along with analytical experience that has proven effective in past projects and work environments.

PROJECTS

LOCALEYES

http://www.localeyestrips.com

An app that connects tourists to day trips curated by locals. Made in 7 days as a group project.

- Built with Ruby on Rails backend and Materialize frontend frameworks (Materialize is based on the Google Material Design philosophy)
- Incorporate Google Maps and Google Places API to retrieve information for created day trips
- Assist with set up of Google Maps integration into web app and logic behind pulling information from Google
- Use JQuery and AJAX for commenting, favoriting and communicating with Google Places API
- Responsible for styling and organizing inbox and messaging system between users; made use of the Mailboxer gem
- Assist with the set up of Facebook OAuth and implementation of Devise security gem

LOWER EAST SIDE FILM FESTIVAL

http://www.les-film-festival.herokuapp.com

A fake film festival website that allows users to review and rate films. Made in 2 days as a group assignment at Dev Bootcamp.

- Built with Ruby on Rails on the backend and Bootstrap CSS framework on the frontend
- Heavy involvment in crafting the app architecture
- · Style and organize pages for each film, which included sections devoted to posting comments and reviews
- Use JQuery and AJAX to enhance user experience with commenting and rating film entries
- Tested with RSpec and Capybara

EMPLOYMENT

KATTEN MUCHIN ROSENMAN LLP

Paralegal

New York, NY Jun 2013 to Mar 2016

- · Coordinate and communicate with partners and associates to complete multi-million dollar loan transactions.
- Keep organized and compiled records of all necessary documents for various loans.
- Oversee the integration and training of new paralegal hires into the firm.
- Analyze patterns in legal documentation to draft correspondences and other documents.
- Coordinate delivery of materials and assist with drafting minor legal documents.

TRIBECA FILM

Acquisitions/Marketing Inter

New York, NY Jan 2015 to Aug 2015

- Generate transactional and revenue performance reports for Tribeca Film titles across various VOD platforms.
- Compile master report of all past, current and future independent titles released as day-and-date.
- Organize VOD data into cumulative spreadsheets for analysis by VP, Acquisitions.
- Take lead on portions of grass root marketing outreach and research for Tribeca titles
- Coordinate legal agreements and invoices for private or festival screenings.

MAGNOLIA PICTURES

arketing/Publicity Interr

New York, NY Jan 2013 to May 2013

- Main liaison for guests via e-mail, phone and at the Magnolia office front desk.
 Compile press information regarding Magnolia releases and organize pertinent items in database for future reference.
- Research business contacts for grassroots marketing campaign and update database.
- Set up promotional materials, prepared a theater and ushered guests as part of a Magnolia premiere screening.

IFC FILMS

Acquisitions Intern

New York, NY Sep 2011 to May 2012

- Attend Tribeca Film Festival as a junior member of the Acquisitions team to screen and cover competition films
- Organize and update IFC's electronic database of films using Filemaker Pro-

• Evaluate and write coverage on films and scripts sought for distribution.

• Draft itineraries for executives and coordinate necessary accommodations.

EDUCATION

Columbia University in the City of New York

B.A. Film Studies 2013

Thesis: The tradition of "mono no aware" in the films of Yasujiro Ozu.

Dev Bootcamp

2016

19-week intensive program focusing on competencies in Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails.